Register of the Kurt Richard Grossmann Papers, 1913-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE FILE, 1936-1972. (Box 5-16)
  - Rheinstrom, H., 1938. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 30)
  - Rias, Berlin, Rundfunkanstalt, 1969-1970. (Folder 13: 31, Reel 16)
  - Ritzel, Gerhard, 1971. (Folder 13: 32, Reel 16)
  - Robinson, Nehemiah, 1953-1959. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 33)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1957. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 34)
  - Rosenbaum, Fritz, 1969. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 35)
  - Rossman, Lena, 1956, 1969. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 36)
  - Rossmeissl, 1968-1972. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 37)
  - Roubicek, Ervin, 1968-1986. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 38)
  - Salomon, Erich, 1939-1940. (Reel 16, Folder 13: 39)
  - Sander, W., 1939. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 40)
  - Saenger, Fritz, 1963-1971. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 41)
  - Schaber, Will, 1966-1972. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 42)
  - Schatzki, Erich, 1958-1971. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 43)
  - Schlesinger, Frank, 1968-1971. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 44)
  - Schramm, Dorothea, 1964. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 45)
  - Schulte, Werner, 1970. (Reel 17, Folder 13: 46)
  - Schulweis, Harold M., 1963. (Folder 13: 47, Reel 17)
  - Schulz, Erwin, 1950. (Folder 13: 48, Reel 17)
  - Schulze-Wilde, Harry, 1969. (Folder 13: 49, Reel 17)
  - Schumacher, Peterjuergen, 1966-1968. (Folder 13: 50, Reel 17)
  - Schuetz, Otto, 1956-1970. (Folder 13: 51, Reel 17)
  - Schwerin, Kurt, 1971. (Folder 13: 52, Reel 17)
  - Seger, Gerhart H., 1956. (Folder 13: 53, Reel 17)
  - Semanario israelita, 1969-1970. (Folder 13: 54, Reel 17)
  - Sender Freies Berlin.
    - 1959. (Folder 14: 1, Reel 17)
    - 1960. (Folder 14: 2, Reel 17)
    - 1961. (Folder 14: 3, Reel 17)
    - 1962. (Folder 14: 4, Reel 17)
    - 1963. (Folder 14: 5, Reel 17)
    - 1964. (Folder 14: 6, Reel 17)
    - 1965. (Folder 14: 7, Reel 17)
    - 1966. (Folder 14: 8, Reel 17)
    - 1967. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 9)
    - 1968. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 10)
    - 1969. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 11)
    - 1970. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 12)
  - Senzig, Guido, 1971. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 13)
  - Seydewitz, Ruth, 1935 (Reel 17, Folder 14: 14)
  - Shiloni, Yisroel, 1968. (Folder 14: 15, Reel 17)
  - Shinnar, Felix, 1953. (Folder 14: 16, Reel 17)
  - Signal-Verlag, 1968-1972. (Folder 14: 17, Reel 17)
  - Silberman, Curt C., 1971-1972. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 18)
  - Silman, Elly, 1946-1947. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 19)
  - Simon, Ernst, 1968-1969. (Reel 17, Folder 14: 20)
  - Soeger, Norbert, 1961-1963. (Folder 14: 21, Reel 17)
  - Sommer, Robert (and family members), 1938-1972. (Folder 14: 22-24, Reel 17)
  - Soesemann, Bernd, 1971. (Folder 14: 25, Reel 17)
  - Spiegel, 1953-1971. (Folder 14: 26, Reel 17)
  - Spiegel, Paul, 1966. (Folder 14: 27, Reel 17)
  - Starke, Richard, 1961-1971. (Folder 14: 28, Reel 17)
  - Staudinger, Hans, 1964-1970. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 29)
  - Stern, 1971. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 30)
  - Stern, Desider, 1970. (Folder 14: 31, Reel 18)
  - Sternfeld, W., 1950. (Folder 14: 32, Reel 18)
  - Steuerwald-Landmann, Anna, 1958-1969. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 33)
  - Stiftung Volkswagenwerk, 1965-1966. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 34)
  - Strauss, Franz J., 1953. (Folder 14: 35, Reel 18)
  - Strauss, Herbert A., 1968-1971. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 36)
  - Studio Radio Bern, 1959. (Folder 14: 37, Reel 18)
  - Stuttgarter Zeitung, 1953-1971. (Folder 14: 38, Reel 18)
  - Sueddeutsche Zeitung, 1953-1971. (Folder 14: 40, Reel 18)
  - Sueddeutscher Rundfunk, 1959-1968. (Folder 14: 39, Reel 18)
  - Suedwestfunk, 1959. (Folder 14: 41, Reel 18)
  - [Syrkin] Marie, 1967-1971. (Folder 14: 42, Reel 18)
  - Tagesspiegel, Berlin, 1948-1970. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 43)
  - Tagwacht, Bern, 1968-1972 (Reel 18, Folder 14: 44)
  - Tartakower, Arieh, 1946. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 45)
  - Teich, Meier, 1969-1970. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 46)
  - Telegraf, Berlin, 1967-1971. (Reel 18, Folder 14: 47)
  - Theodor Herzl Institute, 1957-1972. (Reel 18, Folder 15: 1)
  - Thieme, Karl, 1960-1963. (Reel 18, Folder 15: 2)
  - Tillich, Paul, (photocopy)., 1944 (Reel 18, Folder 15: 3)
  - Time, 1971. (Folder 15: 4, Reel 18)
  - Trenkner, Joachim, 1969-1970. (Folder 15: 5, Reel 18)
  - Tribuene, Bad Homburg, 1968-1970. (Folder 15: 6, Reel 18)
  - Tschuppik, Walter, 1950. (Folder 15: 7, Reel 18)
  - Tuchen, Else, 1969. (Folder 15: 8, Reel 18)
  - Tucholsky, Kurt, (photocopies)., 1933 (Folder 15: 9, Reel 18)
  - Unger, H.-J., 1969. (Folder 15: 10, Reel 18)
  - Union Verlag, 1968. (Folder 15: 11, Reel 18)
  - United Automobile Workers Union, 1970. (Reel 18, Folder 15: 12)
  - United Nations, 1944-1952. (Reel 18, Folder 15: 13-14)
  - United Restitution Organization, 1956-1971. (Reel 18, Folder 15: 15)
  - United States.
    - General (various government agencies), 1943-1968. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 16)
    - President's Advisory Committee on Political Refugees, 1942. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 17)
    - State Department, 1942. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 18)
  - Valentin, Veit, (primarily photocopies)., 1942-1947 (Reel 19, Folder 15: 19)
  - Vogel, Rolf, 1968-1972. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 20)
  - Vorgaenge, 1971-1972. (Folder 15: 21, Reel 19)
  - Vorwaerts, 1972. (Folder 15: 22, Reel 19)
  - Wachenheim, Hedwig, 1969. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 23)
  - Wallach, Frederick, 1970. (Folder 15: 24, Reel 19)
  - Washington Post, The, 1970. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 25)
  - Wechmar, Ruediger Frhr. von, 1963-1971. (Folder 15: 26, Reel 19)
  - Wedel, Emil Graf von, 1956, 1971. (Folder 15: 27, Reel 19)
  - Wegener, Armin T., 1967-1968. (Folder 15: 28, Reel 19)
  - Wegner, Henry, 1970-1972. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 29)
  - Weil, Bruno, 1951-1958. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 30)
  - Weinberg, Hanns, 1948. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 31)
  - Weiss, Ilse Blumenthal, 1957. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 32)
  - Welt, Die, 1965-1972. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 33)
  - Wertheimer, Gunther, 1956. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 34)
  - Wesleyan University Press, 1970. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 35)
  - Westdeutscher Rundfunk, 1959-1968. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 36)
  - Wicclair, Walter, 1967-1971. (Folder 15: 37, Reel 19)
  - Wiener Library, The, 1950-1970. (Folder 15: 38, Reel 19)
  - Wiesenthal, Simon, 1966-1972. (Folder 15: 39-41, Reel 19)
  - Wilk, Gerard H., 1966-1971. (Folder 15: 42, Reel 19)
  - Wille, Werner, 1958-1959. (Folder 15: 43, Reel 19)
  - Willi, Jost Niklaus, 1969-1971. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 44)
  - Wills, John P., 1967-1969. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 45)
  - Windelen, Heinrich, 1966. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 46)
  - Winkel, Nina, 1963, 1971. (Reel 19, Folder 15: 47)
  - Wolfson, Manfred, 1962-1967. (Folder 16: 1, Reel 20)
  - Wollenberg, Otto, 1939. (Folder 16: 2, Reel 20)
  - Wollheim, Norbert, 1947-1972. (Folder 16: 3, Reel 20)
  - World Jewish Congress, 1945-1969. (Folder 16: 4, Reel 20)
  - Wulf, Joseph, 1968-1970. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 5)
  - Yad Vashem, 1963-1971. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 6)
  - Zeit, Die, 1964-1971. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 7)
  - Zimmer, Anneliese, 1960-1973. (Folder 16: 8-10, Reel 20)
  - Zirker, Milly, 1960-1963. (Folder 16: 11, Reel 20)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, c.1933-1972 (Box 16-36)
  Drafts and printed copies of articles, speeches, and books written by or edited by Kurt R. Grossmann, arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Untitled memorandum, re restitution, Mimeographed copy. (Folder 16: 12, Reel 20)
  - Untitled radio broadcast, re American Jews and the new Germany, Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 16: 13, Reel 20)
  - Untitled radio broadcast, re unsung heroes, Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 14)
  - Untitled speech, re Hochhuth's Stellvertreter (The Deputy), Typescript., n.d. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 15)
  - Untitled speech, re Jews in Eastern Europe, Typescript (carbon copy)., 1952 (Reel 20, Folder 16: 16)
  - Untitled speech, re restitution, Mimeographed copy., March 22, 1964. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 17)
  - Untitled speech, re restitution, Typescript., April 14, 1966. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 18)
  - Untitled speech, re restitution in Austria, Typescript and related material., March 30, 1969. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 19)
  - Untitled speech, re Willy Brandt, Typescript and related material., December 10, 1971. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 20)
  - "Aber X hat seine Wiedergutmachung doch schon erhalten," (But X already received his restitution payment), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 18, 1957. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 21)
  - "Das Abkommen Deutschland-Israel ist der erste wichtige Schritt," (The German-Israeli agreement is the first important step), New Yorker Staats-Zeitung, Printed copy., September 11, 1952. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 22)
  - "Abschied von Arieh Kubovy," (Farewell to Arieh Kubovy), Aufbau, Printed copy., June 17, 1966. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 23)
  - "Abschied von der Claims Conference," Aufbau, Printed copy., July 30, 1965. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 24)
  - "Abschied von einem Freund," Aufbau, Printed copy., January 27, 1967. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 25)
  - "Abschied von Franz Schoenberner," Aufbau, Typescript and printed copies., April 17, 1970. (Folder 16: 26, Reel 20)
  - "Abschied von Nehemiah Robinson," Aufbau, Printed copy., January 24, 1964. (Folder 16: 27, Reel 20)
  - "Abwehrkampf des CV vor 1933," (Struggle of the central union of German citizens of Jewish faith before 1933), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 4, 1969. (Folder 16: 28, Reel 20)
  - "825,000 Ansprueche noch unerledigt," (Unsettled claims), Aufbau, Printed copy., July 20, 1962. (Folder 16: 29, Reel 20)
  - "Adolf Leschnitzer - 60 Jahre," (A. L. 60 years old), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., January 30, 1959. (Folder 16: 30, Reel 20)
  - "Agnew gegen Goodell, der Zug nach rechts," (Agnew vs. Goodell, the shift to the right), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 31)
  - "Aktion Suehnezeichen-Erlebnis, Berichte junger Deutscher," (The Aktion Suehnzeichen experience, reports of young Germans), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 14, 1967. (Folder 16: 32, Reel 20)
  - "Albert Einstein und die Deutsche Liga fuer Menschenrechte," (A.E. and the German League for Human Rights), Die Menschenrechte, Printed copy., March-June, 1955. (Folder 16: 33, Reel 20)
  - "Albert John Luthuli und Carl von Ossietzky," Typescript (carbon copies)., October 28, 1961. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 34)
  - "Alleingaenger Simon Wiesenthal, nicht Rache sondern Gerechtigkeit," (The loner S. W., not revenge but justice), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 7, 1967. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 35)
  - "Alles Unglueck kommt von der Erbsuende," (All misfortune comes from original sin), Mimeographed copy and related material., September 1969. (Reel 20, Folder 16: 36)
  - "Der alte Nixon lebt noch," (The old Nixon still lives), Typescript., n.d. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 37)
  - "Altersversorgung durch Wiedergutmachung," (Care for the elderly through restitution), Aufbau, Printed copy., August 4, 1961. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 38)
  - "America the Beautiful?" Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., December 5, 1968. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 39)
  - "Amerika im Zeichen der Gewalt," (America in the thrall of violence), Tagwacht, Printed copy., October, 28, 1970. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 40)
  - "Amerika steuert in die schwerste innere Krise," (America steering through the most severe inner crisis), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., November 1, 1970. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 41)
  - "Amerika und Nixon's Krieg," (America and Nixon's war), Tagwacht, Printed copy., May 11, 1970. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 42)
  - "Das amerikanische Dilemma," Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 10, 1968. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 43)
  - "Das amerikanische Judentum und das moderne Deutschland," (American Jews and modern Germany), Typescript., April 1959. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 44)
  - "Amerikas schwere Schuld," (America's severe guilt), Semana israelita, Printed copies., February 2, 1968. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 45)
  - "Amerikas Studenten sind eine politische Belastung," (America's students are a political liability), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., September 7, 1970. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 46)
  - "Amnestie fuer Deserteure?" Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 7, 1971. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 47)
  - "Der Amsterdamer Weltkongress gegen den imperialistischen Krieg," (The Amsterdam World Congress vs. imperialistic war), Die Friedenswarte, October 1932. (Folder 16: 48, Reel 21)
  - "Analyse der Entschaedigungsstatistik," Die Mahnung, Printed copy., January 15, 1960. (Folder 16: 49, Reel 21)
  - "Analyse der 1970er Wahlen," (Analysis of the 1970 elections), Tagwacht, November 9, 1970. (Folder 16: 50, Reel 21)
  - "Das andere Deutschland, Anmerkungen zum Besuch des Bundespraesidenten in Amerika," (The other Germany, comments on the visit of the German President to America), Neue Presse, Printed copy., July 1, 1958. (Folder 16: 51, Reel 21)
  - "Aendern die USA ihre Richtung?" (Is the US changing direction?) Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., January 20, 1970. (Folder 16: 52, Reel 21)
  - "Die Anderson Enthuellungen," (The Anderson revelations), Jodioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., January 21, 1972. (Reel 21, Folder 16: 53)
  - "Andrang demokratischer Praesidentenschaftkandidaten, das finanzielle und politische Dilemma," (The throng of Democratic presidential candidates, the financial and political dilemma), Typescript., November 23, 1971. (Folder 16: 54, Reel 21)
  - "Angeklagter in einem Diktaturstaat," (The accused in a dictatorship), Aufbau, June 10, 1966. (Folder 17: 1, Reel 21)
  - "Anklage gegen Westmoreland?" (Suit against W.?), Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 18, 1971. (Folder 17: 2, Reel 21)
  - "Eine Annonce in der N.Y. Times," Semana israelita, Printed copy., July 22, 1966. (Folder 17: 3, Reel 21)
  - "Anti-deutsche Gefuehle in USA," (Anti-German sentiments in the US), Mimeographed copies., March 9, 1961. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 4)
  - "Anti-Jewish Trends in Germany," Congress Weekly, Printed and mimeographed copies., July 21, 1958. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 5)
  - "Anti-Semitism in the Last Two Decades: Germany and Western Europe," Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 21, Folder 17: 6)
  - "Antisemitismus ohne Juden, das polnische Phaenomon," (Anti-Semitism without Jews, the Polish phenomenum), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., January 12, 1970. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 7)
  - "Die Antragsfrist Dezember 1969," (The deadline for processing applications, December 1969), Aufbau, Printed copies., September 27, 1968. (Folder 17: 8, Reel 21)
  - "Die Antwort der Juden an Adenauer," (The Jews' answer to Adenauer), Allgemeine, Duesseldorf, November 7, 1951. (Folder 17: 9, Reel 21)
  - "Apollo 15 fuer die USA zu teuer?" (Is Apollo 15 too expensive for the US?), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., August 6, 1971. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 10)
  - "Arab Propaganda Boomerang," press release, The Jewish Agency, Mimeographed copies. (Folder 17: 11, Reel 21)
  - "Arroganz der Macht und Frieden," (The arrogance of power and peace), Tagwacht, Printed copy., January 5, 1972. (Folder 17: 12, Reel 21)
  - "Aerzte und Verfolgte," (Doctors and the persecuted), Aufbau, Printed copy., May 26, 1961. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 13)
  - "Asylum for Refugees under our Immigration Law," Holograph. (Folder 17: 14, Reel 21)
  - "Attica, Symptom einer Krankheit," (Attica, symptom of a disease), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., September 24, 1971. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 15)
  - "Auch in Berlin geht das Entschaedigungswerk dem Ende entgegen," (Even in Berlin the restitution work is nearly finished), Typescript (carbon copy)., 1967. (Folder 17: 16, Reel 21)
  - "Auch Rechtskandidaten sind Referendare," (Even law graduates are officials), Aufbau, Printed copies., May 28, 1965. (Folder 17: 17, Reel 21)
  - "Auch Washington wurde schuldig," (Even Washington was guilty), Der Ausweg, Typescript and printed copies., February 1968. (Folder 17: 18, Reel 21)
  - "Auf dem Mond waere genuegend Platz, aber...Nixon und die drohende Bevoelkerungs-explosion," (There would be enough room on the moon, but...Nixon and the threatening population explosion), Jedioth Chadashoth, September 12, 1968. (Folder 17: 19, Reel 21)
  - "Auf dem Wege zu einer umfassenden Krankenkassenversicherung?" (On the way to a comprehensive health insurance), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 17: 20, Reel 21)
  - "Aufbau," (reconstruction), Typescript notes., n.d. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 21)
  - "Die Augen des Grossen Bruders," (The eyes of Big Brother), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., Feruary 25, 1971. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 22)
  - "Aus Angst gemordet," (Murdering out of fear), Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 23)
  - "Aus unseren Kreisen--Dr. Richard Dann gestorben," (From our circle--R.D. died), Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., January 19, 1968. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 24)
  - "Auschwitz und die Sache der Bruederlichkeit," (Auschwitz and the matter of brotherhood), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 21, Folder 17: 25)
  - "Aussprechen was ist--offener Brief an Dr. Franz Josef Strauss," (Telling the facts--open letter to F.J.S.), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 17: 26, Reel 21)
  - "Auszug der Intelligenz," (Departure of the educated), Rheinischer Merkur, Typescript and printed copies. (Folder 17: 27, Reel 21)
  - "Axel Springer fuer die Pax Americana," Typescript (carbon copy)., November 9, 1971. (Folder 17: 28, Reel 21)
  - "Barry, komm bald wieder--Johnsons neue Gegner sind gefaehrlicher als Goldwater," (Barry, come back soon--Johnson's new opponents are more dangerous than Goldwater), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., February 2, 1967. (Folder 17: 29, Reel 21)
  - "The Basis of the Hague Negotiations," New Yorker Staatszeitung, Reprint., March 18, 1952. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 30)
  - "Ein befremdender Kabinettbeschluss, Bundeskabinett will BRueG-Vorlage aendern," (A disturbing cabinet decision, the German cabinet wants to alter the proposed restitution law), Aufbau, Printed copy., April 17, 1964. (Reel 21, Folder 17: 31)
  - "Bericht ueber die durch die Mauer verletzten Menschenrechte," (Report on the violation of human rights by the Berlin Wall), Typescript and carbon copy. (Folder 17: 32, Reel 21)
  - "Bericht ueber die Studienreise durch die Entschaedigungsgebiete in Westdeutschland," (Report on a study trip through the restitution districts of West Germany), Mimeographed copy., 1957. (Folder 17: 33, Reel 21)
  - "Berlin ehrte die unbesungenen Helden," (Berlin honored the unsung heroes), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 11, 1970. (Folder 17: 34, Reel 21)
  - "Berlin, gruendlich veraendert," (Berlin, fundamentally changed), Aufbau, Printed copy., December 10, 1965. (Folder 17: 35, Reel 21)
  - "Berlin und die unbesungenen Helden," (Berlin and the unsung heroes), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 21, Folder 17: 36)
  - "Die Berliner juedische Gemeinde," (The Berlin Jewish community), Typescript and carbon copy. (Folder 17: 37, Reel 22)
  - "Die Berrigan-Brueder und der Held," (The Berrigan brothers and the hero), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copy., August 25, 1971. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 38)
  - "Bevoelkerungsumschichtung," (Population redistribution), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 21, 1970. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 39)
  - "Bilanz einer Deutschlandreise besonderer Art," (Assessment of a Germany trip of a special kind), Sueddeutsche Zeitung, Printed copy., April 16, 1956. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 40)
  - "Bob Kennedy ist nicht mehr..." (B.K. is no more), Boletin informativo, Printed copy., July 1968. (Folder 17: 41, Reel 22)
  - "Der Bombenwahnsinn in den USA," (The bomb craze in the US), Tagwacht, March 31, 1970. (Folder 17: 42, Reel 22)
  - "Der Bonn-Moskau Vertrag und die USA," (The Bonn Moscow treaty and the US), Typescript (carbon copy). (Folder 17: 43, Reel 22)
  - "Die boese Saat von Memphis," (The evil seed of Memphis), Tagwacht, Printed copy., September 4, 1971. (Folder 17: 44, Reel 22)
  - "Braver Mann Motzko," (Motzko, a decent man), Aufbau, Printed copies., May 27, 1966. (Folder 17: 45, Reel 22)
  - "Brennendes wird nicht diskutiert--23. Vollversammlung der Vereinigten Nationen beginnt," (Buring issues are not discussed, the 23ed full session of the United Nations begins), Vorwaerts, Printed copy., October 3, 1968. (Folder 17: 46, Reel 22)
  - "Brief aus den USA," (Letter from the US), Semana Israelita, Printed copy., July 1966. (Folder 17: 47, Reel 22)
  - "Ein Brief nach Deutschland," (A letter to Germany), Der Tagesspiegel, Printed copy., October 16, 1946. (Folder 17: 48, Reel 22)
  - "Brief von einem amerikanischen Freund an einen jungen Deutschen," (Letter from an American friend to a young German), Typescript. (Folder 17: 49, Reel 22)
  - "Die Bruecke ueber den Abgrund, Ich lebe nicht in der Bundesrepublik," (The bridge over the abyss, I do not live in Germany), Galley proofs. (Folder 17: 50, Reel 22)
  - "Bullerjahn frei...nach acht Jahren hat das Recht gesiegt," (Bullerjahn free, after eight years justice is victorious), Photocopies of printed article., n.d. (Folder 17: 51, Reel 22)
  - "Der Bundeskanzler muss handeln!" (The German chancellor must act!), Sozialdemokratischer Pressedienst, Mimeographed copies., June 1, 1964. (Folder 17: 52, Reel 22)
  - "Carl von Ossietzky--ganz der Alte! Erstes Gespraech mit ihm nach seiner Haftentlassung," (C. von O.--the same as ever! First conversation with him after his release from prison), Photocopies of printed article., n.d. (Folder 17: 53, Reel 22)
  - "Carl von Ossietzky--nach sechsundzwanzig Jahren," (C. von O.--after 26 years), Typescript (carbon copy). (Reel 22, Folder 17: 54)
  - "Carl von Ossietzky Receives the Peace Nobel Prize," Printed copy., n.d. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 55)
  - "Carl von Ossietzky und die Gegenwart, zum 30. Todestag des Friedens nobel preistraegers," (C. von O. and the present, on the 30th anniversary of the death of the Nobel Peace Prize winner), Boletin informativo, Typescript and printed copy., July 1968. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 56)
  - "Changing Times--Changing Morals: Moral Transformations of the Federal Republic of Germany," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 57)
  - "Chaplain Joseph S. Shubow," Aufbau, Typescript and printed copy., August 29, 1969. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 58)
  - "A Chapter in Polish-German Understanding: The German League for Human Rights," The Polish Review, Printed copy., Summer 1970. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 59)
  - "Charleston, South Carolina, oder USA heute," (C., S. C., or the US today), Jedioth Chadashoth, Printed copy., July 11, 1969. (Folder 17: 60, Reel 22)
  - "Der Chicagoer Konspirationsprozess," (The Chicago conspiracy trial), Tagwacht, Typescript and printed copies., October 7, 1969. (Folder 17: 61, Reel 22)
  - "Der Chicago-Prozess und die Haynsworth Bestaetigung," (The Chicago trial and the Haynsworth confirmation), Typescript (carbon copy)., November 12, 1969. (Folder 17: 62, Reel 22)
  - "Chinas Sieg in der UNO," (China's victory in the U.N.), Tagwacht, Printed copy., December 1, 1970. (Folder 17: 63, Reel 22)
  - "Christian Geissler und die Zeit-Anfrage, Eindruecke von einer Studienreise durch die Bundesrepublik," (C.G. seeking information: impressions of a study trip through West Germany), Aufbau, November 11, 1960. (Reel 22, Folder 17: 64)
  - "Chronik oder Geschichte? Antwort an E.G. Lowenthal," (Chronicle or history? Answer to E.G. Lowenthal), Typescript., n.d. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 1)
  - "Civilians in a Future War," Jewish Affairs, Printed copies., June-July 1950. (Reel 22, Folder 18: 2)
  - "Clark Clifford und Richard Nixon," Tagwacht, Printed copy., June 25, 1969. (Folder 18: 3, Reel 22)
  - "Come-Back of Hitler's Wolves," World Jewish Affairs, Mimeographed copy., May 22, 1957. (Folder 18: 4, Reel 22)
  - "The Creator of the Geneva Convention," Typescript (carbon copy)., n.d. (Folder 18: 5, Reel 22)
  - "Cui bono: Mr. Nixon?" Jedioth Chadashoth, Typescript and printed copy., July 3, 1970. (Folder 18: 6, Reel 22)
  - "Damit wir nicht vergesson," (So that we do not forget), Aufbau, Printed copy., October 27, 1967. (Folder 18: 7, Reel 22)
  - "Danzigs elastische Polenpolitik," (Danzig's elastic Poland policy), Die Wahrheit, Prague, Printed copy., August 18, 1934. (Folder 18: 8, Reel 22)